<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Becky&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Becky&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing and Visualizing Data in Python</title>
      <link>/blog/organizing-and-visualizing-data-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/organizing-and-visualizing-data-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! Welcome to my very first blog post. This beginner level guide will show you various ways of organizing and visualizing data using Python. Everything is at the beginner level! Let’s get started.
For this tutorial style walkthrough, we’ll be working with the pokemon dataset, renamed ‘poke’ here for convenience. The python packages ‘pandas’ and ‘seaborn’ will come in handy too!
Now that we are somewhat familiar with the dataset, we could start organizing and trying different functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Data With Python</title>
      <link>/2020/05/09/organizing-data-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/09/organizing-data-with-python/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Becky Lee bsl668
###1: Introduction
#####The dataset `weather’, aquired from a list of data in R, contains 15 variables and 26,115 observations. As an individual who checks the weather daily, this dataset caught my attention. In addition, there was a wide number and variety of variables, which would give flexibility when tinkering with the data. The 15 variables include origin, a time ID, year, month, day, hour, temperature, dew point, humidity, wind direction, wind speed, wind gust, precipitation, pressure, and visibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Becky Lee bsl668
0: IntroductionThe ‘infert’ dataset in R was used for this project. Some information regarding the dataset was found online, due to some difficulty interpreting the variables and background of the study. The dataset is officially titled “Infertility after Spontaneous and Induced Abortion” and is based on a study published in 1976. The study aimed to see if there was a connection between infertility and abortions, both induced and spontaneous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs</title>
      <link>/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Blogs Here are my blog posts:
 Blog 1: Organizing and Visualizing Data with Python  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here is some of my past work:
  Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>